# **Carson Bruce (Work in progress)**

## I am passionate when creating simple and beautiful apps.

I take interest in the entire software development process. Through from the start when a project is imagined towards its end as a project is released. I have experienced a range of roles and tasks covering its broad range.

I consider some of my key skills to include: Problem solving, Speed to learn, Openmindedness, Being a team player, and Communication.

I am a year-zero adopter of JavaScript technologies, Angular, React, Node.js, and Express, embracing the continuing shift towards simplier and more agile systems and process. I love working with JavaScript and all the technologies and processes it enables.

Come say hi at hello@carson.kiwi

## **Experience**

#### **Solnet**

Aug 2012 - Now ( 3.5 years )

I started Solnet a week out from graduating kicking off the role straight into the delivery team of the company. A year in I moved on over into the Digital team where my love for JavaScript and appreciation for UX boomed. I have gained experience with several high profile clients placed first as a developer along with other roles such as devops, ux, team lead, tech lead. More recently in my time at Solnet I have been involved in mentoring others in JavaScript tooling and practices. See the following Projects section for an overview of some of the work I've done at Solnet.

## **Research Project: Query Expansion**

Nov 2011 - March 2012 (4 months)

My second research opportunity was offered by the supervisor of my honours project to further its report towards an end goal of a published research paper. With some give and take from the wider Web Intellegence team at Victoria I managed to get the paper submitted and accepted to an Australasian Web Intellegence conference by the end of my research.

### **Research Project: Eye Gaze tracking**

Nov 2010 - March 2011 (4 months)

I was awarded a research scholarship at the end of my 300 level university year giving me experience in planning directing a research project. With support from my supervisor and his team, I contributed to development on an open source gaze

tracking system helping it evolve to a level where it might benefit the university, saving an equivelant commercial product cost of \$10,000. In addition to learning about eye-tracking systems I gained experience in project practice and guickly learned C#.

#### **Cool Bananas**

Nov 2009 - March 2010 ( 4 months )

Interning with a fellow student alongside a senior software engineer I worked on a project developing a prototype scripting parser and runtime for embedded systems. The experience helped cement my years study learning C, Agile processes, and testing practices. The project proved successful gaining further funding being developed into a commercial product.

## **Education**

**Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Software Engineering, First Class Honours** 

**Victoria University of Wellington** *2007-2012* 

## **Projects**

## **Employment Agreement Builder**

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

EAB is a web application realised to provide value to both front end users along with those responsible for its maintenance. Small to medium business parties are able to use the tool to step through creating a new Employment agreement while at the same time educating themselves about employment law with easy to digest content and links. I lead the implementation design while mentoring a Senior Java developer transitioning to JavaScript. The project ran successfully meeting its internal and external objectives finishing in three months.

- Practiced BDD and TDD development processes ending up with a feature complete automated test suite
- Created a reusable data-driven forms solution that would support future contract builders for MBIE
- Helped sell a through and through Javascript solution internally to Solnet and externally to MBIE
- Went beyond the static wireframes creating my own motion design and micro user interactions
- Created a Node.js micro services implementation handles 10x expected load on low cost two node cloud infastructure
- Created a decoupled CMS component to support the application that provided more features than the Javascript CMS landscape at the time - see

cmeasy.herokuapp.com

Created internal email, document, form components already reused on other
.

projects

Created security implementation that sailed through 3rd party security review

• Implemented a CI environment that performed automated testing and releases a

dozen times a day avoid any manual tasks

• Pushed docker solution handling node scaling, static servers and bringing build and

deployment time down to minutes rather than hours

#### **NEON**

Sky Television

• Managed my time effectively within a time critical environment completing and

communicating tasks to project managers

• Collaberated with UX and design teams ensuring good usability of solution

Presented UX and design solution alternatives to client

• Worked remotely for half the project while still tracking my tasks without issue

### **Online Banking**

Westpac

Originally going in as a dev ops and IBM Worklight consulant - after several months, as

the teams trust grew, my role expanded.

• Presented and owned the solutions of several developer tooling and experience

improvements

• Technical leader and mentor of a team five large covering a wide spread of

technologies and environments

- Trusted as the gatekeeper of critical development and test environments relied on by a team 60 large
- Designed, implemented, and tested a JavaScript middleware framework that improved the abstraction and reliability of the middleware HTTP adaptors
- Designed, implemented, and tested the security feature encompassing the client and middleware layers
- Presented a UX review noting several usability and performance improvements for the application

#### **Air Forms**

Air New Zealand

- · Data driven forms
- Hybrid application design running on Supersonic
- Polished the application removing dozens of browser rendering bottlenecks providing a jank free hybrid solution

## Learning clients name game

**Private** 

We entered in a competition to imagine, design, and develop a proof of concept mobile gamification app in 3 days. Our UX and developer streams worked well together from the start, laying foundations for one another and we managed to create a complete working iOS game that would quiz the user on peoples names with multiple minigames supported by a global leaderboard. We placed well in the competition winning the prize of placing in the companies evaluation panel for future projects followed shortly after with a winning proposal for a separate project.

- Created a complete proof of concept application in 3 days
- Succeeded in gaining a position on the clients project panel
- Hybrid application design
- Super agile
- Worked effectively with other JavaScript, UX and UI developers in parallel

## **Employee Cost Calculator**

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

- · Created proof of concept application as presales
- Contributed to the RFP solution design and estimates
- Designed and implemented Google Analytics solution
- Managed UAT test handover

#### **Public website**

Solnet

Full-stack javascript project Solo developer picking up JavaScript, CSS, HTML

- Self managed team
- Collaberated closely with designer and UX roles
- HTML, CSS, JS development
- Implemented Node.js SEO and decoupled static content

#### **ACC**

Shared Capability

#### Little bite of javascript gave me the curse

- Java developer
- Quick learner
- Enterprise application environments
- Successfully integrated IBM Forms Experience Builder product with IBM Portal collaberating with IBM development team and providing development experience solutions

## **Interests**

Javascript	User Experience	Netball
Running	Cycling	Photography
Gaming	Sound systems	Beer brewing
	Stenciling	

	(https://github.com/Kauabunga)	
<u>(h</u> t	ttps://nz.linkedin.com/in/carsonbruce)	